Clayton J. Lewis

2117 Rene Court. Apt. 2F Ridgewood, NY, 11385 775-233-7630 Cjlewis07@yahoo.com

SUMMARY:

I'm a technical professional that takes pride in having versatile knowledge in various systems and workflows. I've proven to be consistent in completing key projects to accurate completion in addition to making an influential contribution by applying my vast experience and incredible work ethic.

WORKING EXPERIENCE:

Spectrum News NY1 - New York, NY Media Ingest Editor (07/2019- Present)

Preforming with Dalet (MAM) software to record media by way of decoders and fiber feed lines in addition to the asset ingestion of video content from camera cards and third-party sources. Operating a Harris Router for delegated task such as quality control checks and distributing video content for Spectrum affiliates. Remotely coordinating live shows for shoot locations and IFB checks. Fulfilling auxiliary assignments such as segment replay cuts, video asset placement, archival restores and troubleshooting system malfunctions.

Meredith Corporation – New York, NY Video Ingest Technician (09/2018- 07/2019)

Worked with Evolphin Zoom (MAM) software for video ingestion while coordinating the accurate metadata for specific assets for media archival storage. Distinguished various video codecs for appropriate transcoding methods in addition to troubleshooting asset and system software failures. Worked with camera cards, hard drives, video and studio exports while executing proper file transfer protocol for media asset organization. Effectively communicated with VAM, studio, and brand teams to maintain a successful media operation.

Adobe Stock Media – New York, NY Coordinator, Media Operations (02/2017- 08/2018)

Directly responsible for the coordination of media assets delivered from premium contributors and successfully distributed their content into feasible workloads for the creative team's online moderation process. Executed proper file transfer protocol, project setup, and asset storage through DF Studio (DAM) software. Preformed auxiliary duties such as FTP assisted uploads, metadata indexation, and media ingestion.

Overlooked the shipping and receiving of contributor hard drives. Fulfilled various request regarding inventory reports, asset removals, file conversions, and troubleshooting issues. Clearly identified system affairs such as software malfunctions, ingestion failures, and contributor account discrepancies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND ATTRIBUTES:

Computer Programs and Software: MacOS, Windows, Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office, Google Drive Project Management Software: Jira, Trello, Wrike, WebEx, Slack Software Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, CLI, GitHub

- Positive attitude with an enthused desire to learn.
- Powerful sense of urgency and detail in a professional work atmosphere.
- Passionate in providing excellence service to valued clients and customers.

EDUCATION:

State University of New York College at Buffalo:

Bachelor of Arts, Media Production- May 2014

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVIES:

- Software Engineer Intern for Neetos Inc. (2018-Present)
- Head Coach for Ice Hockey in Harlem Program (2016- Present)
- Professional Line Cooking Experience (2013-2018)
- Buffalo State Bengals Men's NCAA Division III Hockey Team (2010-2014)